ENTRY-LEVEL IT PROFESSIONAL

A fall 2022 Computer Science Graduate and Combat Veteran with five years of active-duty experience with one deployment. Served honorably with two military intelligence (MI) analyst military occupational specialties (MOS). Supervised a team of three while accomplishing the missions set forth by leadership. Demonstrated ability to develop and implement effective solutions strategies. Professionally engage with co-workers and management to drive performance. Tactful and diplomatic interpersonal, client relationship, and people management abilities. Effective interpersonal, oral, and written communication skills with the ability to interact with all levels of people within and outside the organization. Ability to follow directions and use logical thought process to interpret oral and written instructions and troubleshoot problems. Work well both independently and within a team environment. Remain focused on exceptional customer service, both internally and externally.

Software Design and Development ● Computer Architecture and Networks ● Problem Solving

Work Independently ● Team Player ● Initiative ● Communications

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript • C++ • Java • Python • PowerPoint • SQL • NoSQL

EDUCATION

SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY

Anticipated October 2022

BS, Computer Science; Concentration in Software Engineering; GPA 3.87

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MCDONALD COOP EQUITY

May 2016-October 2020

Grain Transportation Engineer

- Operated basic farming equipment per OSHA regulations.
- Conducted basic safety inspections and briefings prior to dangerous equipment use.
- Trained and advised staff and customers on basic computer functionality and troubleshooting philosophies.

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

UNITED STATES ARMY

June 2010-January 2015

Specialist, June 2010-January 2015

- Trained and advised soldiers on basic combat practices, welfare practices, and served as an uncertified college algebra tutor.
- Responsible for a multimillion-dollar piece of equipment.
- Conducted daily briefings to outgoing convoys in a deployed environment.

35G (Imagery Analyst), October 2011-January 2015

- Analyzed overhead and aerial imagery developed by photographic and electronic means.
- Provided Commanders and Supported Forces with critical information about enemy forces, potential battle areas and combat operations.
- Supported the various stages of the operation ranging from Future Operation to Post Operation and Battle Damage Assessment.

35H (Common Ground Station Analyst), August 2010-October 2011

- Supervised, performed, and coordinated collection management, analysis, processing, and dissemination of strategic and tactical intelligence.
- Integrated, analyzed, and prioritized All Source Eyelid Reports.
- Assisted in preparing indicators to satisfy priority intelligence requirements.